GIGIL JACOB

RPRA 10, Radha Oil Mill Road, Pachalam, Ernakulam - 682 012 | +91 7907991562 | gigiljacob93@gmail.com |

Professional Summary

Python developer with experience of 4+ years and have been a part of various projects with various frameworks. Gained hands-on experience in developing industrial standard projects during my overall period. Looking forward to learning more about technologies and to implementing them at my opportunity and also to become a pythoneer.

Professional Experience

• Ndimensionz Solutions Pvt Ltd -- Software Engineer

Mar 2022 - Present

Developing different domains of python using various frameworks. Handling api development and other related tech stack using python.

• Mindcoopers -- Software Engineer

June 2019 - Feb 2022 (2yrs 9mos)

Experienced in handling Django projects for creating PEP8 standard of back-end code and collaborating with front end. Capable of handling server instances in AWS and also have knowledge in Nginx configuration. During the period also created several RESTful APIs for various projects and has hands-on experience in implementing power bi reports in web portals. Also have knowledge in implementing payment gateways using Braintree, Stripe, etc...

• BlackVoid -- Python Developer

Nov 2018 - May 2019 (7mos)

Experienced with PyQt5 and creating standalone desktop applications. Handled Django-based web application also managed the team to develop web applications using python frameworks.

RoadELabs -- Python Intern

Jul 2018 - Oct 2018 (4mos)

Worked as Python developer to implement image processing using OpenCV and analyzing the video input using the python framework.

Professional Education

UC College, Ernakulam
UCAS, Ernakulam
Bsc Comp Sci
MG University
MG University

Skill Set

Tools & Technologies

Python, Django, PostgreSql, HTML, CSS, JS, Nginx, AWS, RestAPI, Docker, GitHub, Firebase, PowerBi, BrainTree, Stripe

Interpersonal Skills

Agile, Tean & Solo Player, Leadership

Other Skills

GIMP, MS word, PyCharm

Projects

1. Vineyards

Technologies Used

Django, Python, Jinja-2, PostgreSQL, RestAPI, Nginx, Docker, Power BI, Azure active directory, Lets Encrypt for SSL, Slack API integration, HTML, CSS, JS, JQuery, GitHub, Docker

Roles & Responsibilities

Created Django web portal with database PostgreSQL. Implemented PowerBi reports and free SSL using certbot of open source lets encrypt. Managed basic docker orchestration using nginx and also been a part of the deployment team. Created several Restful Apis using django

2. The Daily Shift

Technologies Used

Django, Python, Jinja-2, RestAPI, Firebase, Stripe, Nginx, Docker

Roles & Responsibilities

Developed and deployed APIs to interact with mobile devices. Integrated subscription according to the subscription plans using Stripe payment gateway.

3. QR Check In

<u>Technologies Used</u>

Django, Python, PostgreSQL, Braintree, Nginx

Roles & Responsibilities

Developed and deployed a web portal using Django and PostgreSQL to identify the customers in a restaurant. Generate QR codes for each of the tables in the restaurant. Generated APIs for smooth communication between two modules. Integrated Subscription using the Braintree payment gateway.

4. NCGA(The National Corn Growers Association)

Technologies Used

Django, Python, MsSQL, Braintree, Nginx, LetsEncrypt.

Roles & Responsibility

Scheduled Python scripts as a cronjob in the Linux server to create and update a new member from NCGA to the Voter Voice system. Identify and fetch all active surveys from the Voter Voice and save those surveys and their responses to the NCGA database. Integrated auto-renewal subscription by creating an API to communicate between NCGA existing systems and Braintree.

5. High Life

Technologies Used

Django, Python, Jinja-2, PostgreSQL, Braintree, AWS S3, Nginx, Docker.

Roles & Responsibilities

Developed a backend to upload photos and videos to AWS S3 and created a pre-signed URL to fetch the same from the S3 bucket. Implemented Braintree with python to purchase a subscription for additional storage. Designing models with CRUD implementation for student's profiles.

6. Kioraa

Technologies Used

AWS S3, AWS EC2, AWS RDS, AWS Load Balancer, Nginx, Certbot (Opensource SSL)

Roles & Responsibilities

Manage the server and configuration in AWS using Nginx. For SSL certificate lets-encrypt has been integrated.

Declaration

I hereby declare that all information said to be true to the best of my knowledge

[GIGIL JACOB]

420-4